Open the menu[](https://www.mailo.com/ "Mailo home page")

|     |     |
| --- | --- |

Privacy rules
=============

_Publication date: May 20th, 2019._

_Modified on December 10th, 2020._

Object
------

As part of the provision of its services, Mailo is brought to proceed to the storage and to the processing of your personal data. This Privacy Rules is an integral part of the Mailo Terms of Use and are intended to indicate what data is stored and how it is used, how you can access, update, and delete your data. Mailo is committed to respect your privacy and your personal data according to these rules.

All transactions on personal data are carried out in compliance with the regulations in force in France, including Law No. 78-17 "Informatique et Libertés" of January 6, 1978, modified in compliance with the European Data Protection Regulation ([GDPR](https://www.eugdpr.org/)), effective since 2018. Exchanges are subject to the secrecy of correspondence, as defined in Articles [226-15](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichCodeArticle.do?cidTexte=LEGITEXT000006070719&idArticle=LEGIARTI000006417954&dateTexte=20090620) and [432-9](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichCodeArticle.do?cidTexte=LEGITEXT000006070719&idArticle=LEGIARTI000006418511&dateTexte=&categorieLien=cid) of the French Penal Code and Article L 33-1 of the French [Post and Electronic Communications Code](https://www.legifrance.gouv.fr/affichCode.do?cidTexte=LEGITEXT000006070987).

Your data
---------

You provide some data directly, such as when you create a Mailo account, upload a document to the virtual disk, or ask for help. Mailo also generates data for purely technical purposes. Any use of the data for purposes other than those set forth in this Privacy Rules requires your explicit agreement.

### 1\. Your account data

To access Mailo services, you must create an account. For this purpose, you provide personal information that you explicitly fill in such as your first and last name, your e-mail address, your date of birth or your language. The mandatory or optional nature of the data is indicated in the collection forms. To create a personal account, entering the date of birth is required to verify that you are at least 16 years old or have parental authorization. The first name, last name and date of birth will be requested if you want to recover access to your account in case of loss of password.  
To take advantage of all the features and to personalize your experience, you may need to complete your profile, indicate your gender, your mobile phone number, your postal address and upload a photo.  
Your e-mail address may be used by Mailo to communicate with you, for example to provide you with information about your account, Services and security updates, or to conduct satisfaction surveys. You may object to this type of communication at any time by email at contact@mailo.com.  
You can view, modify or delete your personal data at any time in your Mailo account by going to the options in the Profile section. In case of modification, Mailo does not keep the profiles previously modified and replaced.  
Your profile information can be displayed to facilitate communication, collaboration, and file sharing with other users.

**Account creation and last access date**  
Mailo retains for technical reasons the date of creation of your account and date of last access to the account.

**Login history**  
So you can have an overview of your use of Mailo services and to check that no abnormal connection to your account has occurred, the history of your sessions (date of connection, type of connection and IP address) is stored for 1 month. This data is deleted automatically after one month. In addition, you can access them at any time in the Options under the heading Your account and delete them yourself.

**Communication history with Mailo**  
When you contact Mailo by e-mail, a history of exchanges is kept to understand and solve the problems you encounter.

**Configuration data and preferences**  
Mailo stores data related to setting up and to the use of the services you use. This includes, but is not limited to, message templates, filters, RSS feeds, current share data, or the list of configured reminders.

### 2\. Contents you entrust to Mailo

Mailo services let you communicate, store files, collaborate with other users, and work on multiple devices. To make this possible and easy to use, Mailo stores, processes and transmits the content you entrust to it (such as your messages, files, photos, events and contacts).

**Processing your content**  
It is reminded that the email is subject to the secrecy of correspondence. Mailo does not use what you say in e-mails or chats, or your documents, photos, address book or other personal files to send you targeted advertising or enrich a database which could be sold.  
To ensure your security (antivirus and antispam) or to improve your use of email (graymail filtering), Mailo automatically analyzes all e-mails. These processes are performed on Mailo servers. You can disable them in Options, in the E-mail reception section.

**Content you share**  
Some Mailo services, such as the virtual disk or calendar, allow you to share your data with others. Be aware that the people you share your content with can then use, copy, save, transmit and display these contents. When you share contents publicly, they may be indexed by search engines.

**Backing up or exporting your content**  
To download all of your content stored on Mailo (e-mails, contacts, diaries, notes, etc.) and use them on another service as part of the right to portability, you can go to the Options in the Data Export topic.

### 3\. Operating data

Mailo automatically generates data to ensure the proper functioning of its services, improve and protect them.

**Log files**  
To administer the platform and ensure its proper functioning, Mailo saves "log files" that may contain the IP address of your connection and the type and language of the browser you use. These files are consulted only in case of technical problem of operation and / or correction of malfunction are kept for 1 month then deleted automatically.

**Operating tickets**  
To monitor and analyze the activity of the platform and meet its legal obligations, Mailo stores and stores in operating tickets a set of operations performed on an account, for example account creations, alias creations , pack purchases and metadata for receiving and sending e-mails. This information is kept for a minimum of 1 year.

**Cookies**  
As a reminder, cookies are small data files which allow keep information in the browser. They are posted by websites to identify the browser and follow it from page to page. Internet sites can only access cookies that have been stored by themselves on the browser.

**Session cookies**  
For the operation of the service, and especially for its security, Mailo uses cookies, named session cookies.  
These cookies only contain a temporary code allowing Mailo to identify the user during their session on the service. No record of this code is kept by Mailo at the end of the session.  
If the user chooses to be recognized automatically on each return visit to Mailo, a cookie is stored on their browser to this purpose. This cookie contains a code which cannot be humanly interpreted.  
These cookies are declared on the domain names of Mailo: "mailo.com", "net-c.com" and "netcourrier.com".

**Advertising cookies and consent**  
In the free version of Mailo, Mailo Free, advertisement banners are displayed. The advertising agencies can deposit advertising cookies on your browser in order to customize the displayed banners.  
The deposit of these cookies is subject to your consent, in compliance with the Specifications and Policies of the Transparency & Consent Framework of the IAB Europe. To this end, Mailo uses the Consent Management Platform #92, operated by the company Sirdata. To memorize your choice, a cookie is stored on the domain name "consentframework.com". You can modify your choice at any time in the Your account page of Mailo, by clicking on the "Manage the deposit of advertising cookies" button. You can learn more about [Sirdata personal data protection and privacy policy](https://www.sirdata.com/privacy/) and [disable the collect of your data by Sirdata](https://www.sirdata.com/opt-out/).  
Each advertising cookie is stored on the domain name of the advertising agency which has deposited it. The advertising agencies can have their own partners which can also display advertising banners and deposit cookies under their own domain names.  
The cookies declared under the domain name of the consent platform, the agencies or their partners are in no case related to your Mailo profile or account.

Permissions requested by the mobile application
-----------------------------------------------

To be able to operate and offer a complete and efficient service, the Mailo mobile application requests authorizations or permissions during its installation.

**iOS**  
By default, the Mailo application requests access to contacts. This permission allows you to provide access to the e-mail addresses of contacts stored on your phone when you write an e-mail in the application. Your mobile contacts are automatically synced to your Mailo address book only if you request it. To do this, go to the application Options in the Contacts section. The contacts access can be revoked in the Settings of the device.

**Android**  
In order to operate, the Mailo application for Android requires the following permissions:  
\- have full network access: only used to communicate with the Mailo servers  
\- read the contents of your SD card, modify or delete the contents of your SD card: used to store or add attachments and use the virtual disk  
\- change your audio settings, prevent your device from sleeping, control vibration: used to notify of the arrival of new messages  
\- read your contacts, modify your contacts, find accounts on the device: to synchronize contacts between the phone or the tablet and the Mailo account : to provide access to the e-mail addresses of the contacts stored on your phone when you write an e-mail in the application and to able to synchronize - at your request only - the contacts of your mobile phone with your Mailo address book. To do this, go to the Application Options in the Contacts section.  
Permissions can be revoked in device Settings in the Applications section and in the Mailo entry.

Requests from the authorities
-----------------------------

Mailo may be required to provide data to the police, gendarmerie and justice authorities in a strict legal framework with the authorization of a magistrate.

Sharing with technical partners
-------------------------------

In 2 very specific cases, Mailo is brought to communicate to his technical partners some of your personal information.  
1) When you make a purchase by credit card or PayPal on Mailo, your e-mail address is shared with Verifone/Paybox secure payment solutions provider ([www.paybox.com](https://www.paybox.com/)).  
2) As part of a domain name purchase, Mailo communicates to the Gandi registrar ([www.gandi.net](https://www.gandi.net/)) the mandatory information such as your first name, last name, postal address and e-mail address.  
Apart from these two cases, Mailo does not communicate any of your personal data to third parties. In particular, Mailo does not transmit any information to its advertising agencies.

Data security
-------------

Mailo implements all necessary security measures with regard to the nature of your data, in order to guarantee their security and confidentiality and, in particular, to prevent them from being deformed, damaged or unauthorized third parties have access to it.  
In particular :  
\- most Mailo services are encrypted using SSL technology;  
\- Mailo conducts internal audits on the collection, storage and processing of data to prevent unauthorized access to our systems;  
\- Access to personal data is strictly limited to employees responsible for the maintenance and evolution of Mailo. These people are subject to strict confidentiality obligations.

Retention and deletion of data
------------------------------

Your personal data is kept throughout the life of your Mailo account.  
When you delete your content (messages, contacts, events, files), these are permanently deleted from Mailo servers.  
To completely delete your account, you can go to the Options under Your Account. When you delete your account, the associated contents are kept for one month for technical reasons, then permanently deleted by the system. However, if you want your content to be permanently deleted when you close the account, you can delete it before closing.  
Mailo stores and processes your personal data and content on servers located in France.

Data Protection Officer
-----------------------

To exercise your rights or for any question regarding the management of your data on Mailo, you can get in touch with our Data Protection Officer at the address contact@mailo.com.

|     |     |
| --- | --- |

### More information

### Useful links

### Discover Mailo

### More info on Mailo

* ### Social networks

Notifications

The session has expired

Warning: you seem to be offline
